So my voice should be coming from there, right?
我的声音应该从那边传出来吧？
It's going through there.
正在通过那里
It's going to be outputted out of here, and it's going to be connected to the Zoom recording.
它将从这里输出  并将连接到 Zoom 录制
Test, test.
测试  测试
Zoom, can you hear me?
Zoom  你能听到我吗？
Yes.
可以
All right, perfect.
好的  完美
Can you get out the current schedule?
你能拿出目前的日程安排吗？
Current spring 24 schedule.
当前春季24课程表
I'd like to do a kind of recap of what assignments are due soon.
我想回顾一下哪些作业快到截止日期了
All right.
好的
We're about to get started.
我们马上就要开始了
How's everyone doing?
大家都好吗？
All right.
好的
Let's see.
让我们看看
What assignments do we have?
我们有哪些作业？
Let's see. What assignments do we have so far?
让我们看看   到目前为止我们有哪些作业？
I have 30 seconds. Let's see.
我还有 30 秒   让我们看看
Quick, quick. Seems like today is the 12th.
快点快点   今天好像是12号了
So Lab 10 is due today.
所以实验10今天截止
Make sure you get that done.
确保你完成了
Project 3A, it's going to be due on Monday.
项目3A  将在周一截止
Make sure you finish that as quickly as possible.
确保你尽快完成
The rest of this class, it's largely about Project 3.
这门课的剩余部分  主要内容是关于项目3的
So it's time to get creative on that aspect.
所以是时候在那方面发挥创造力了
So today, we have another one of our software engineering lecturers.
所以今天  我们还有一位软件工程讲师
And today's guest lecturer is a TA, Ergun.
今天客座讲师是助教Ergun
Yeah. So I think we're ready to start.
是的   我想我们准备开始了
You ready?
你准备好了吗？
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, let's go.
好的  开始吧
I'll hand it off.
我来交接
And now we can start recording.
现在我们可以开始录制了
I think this is fine, right?
我认为这样就可以了  对吧？
And I talked to you.
我和你说过了
Yeah, you sound good.
是的  你听起来不错
Sound good?
听起来不错？
OK, perfect.
好的  完美
You good to go?
准备好了吗？
All right. Hello.
好的   大家好
Today we'll be going over Software Engineering 3 lecture.
今天我们将回顾软件工程 3 的课程内容
My name is Argun. I'm a fourth year computer science major from Istanbul, Turkey.
我叫 Argun   我是来自土耳其伊斯坦布尔的一名四年级计算机科学专业学生
This is my fifth semester on staff, and I like cats, geography, and traveling.
这是我在职的第五个学期  我喜欢猫、地理和旅行
And today, I will be firstly talking about my experience with a project called Gillet when I was a freshman back in 2021 spring.
今天  我首先要谈谈我在 2021 年春季大一时参与的一个名为 Gillet 项目的经验
Right, project2-gitlit.
好的  project2-gitlit 项目
Let me show it to you real quick.
让我快速展示一下
Well, I cannot get out of here.
好吧  我无法退出这里
But OK, that's fine then.
但是好吧  那没关系
So the project2-gitlit was basically a version control system, implementing a version control system in your computer.
所以 project2-gitlit 项目基本上是一个版本控制系统  在你的计算机中实现了一个版本控制系统
And it was my first big scale project.
这是我的第一个大型项目
The spec was very long.
规范很长
And there were, I think, 10 to 15 videos.
而且  我想有 10 到 15 个视频
And it was very, very hard to understand project after project one.
在项目1之后  这个项目非常非常难理解
We are not doing project GitLit as project 2 anymore, but we have a similar project.
我们不再将 GitLit 项目作为项目 2  但我们有一个类似的项目
As a disclaimer, this is my own personal experience with Gillet and everything
声明一下  这是我个人使用 Gitlet 的经验
I say from here until the end of the Gillet part should be taking us from my perspective.
从现在到 Gitlet 部分结束  我所说的所有内容都是从我的角度出发的
What is Gillet?
什么是 Gitlet？
It's TLDR implementing your own version of control system, as I said, like you get in real life.
简单来说  它就是实现你自己的版本控制系统  就像你在现实生活中使用的那样
And as a freshman, I was introduced to my first big scale project
作为一名大一新生  我第一次接触到大型项目
from none to little list skeleton code, creating a design document and comprehensive multiple testing.
从零开始  只有一些基本的框架代码  需要创建设计文档和全面的多重测试
Randomized test to prevent the hard coding and brute forcing the grader.
随机测试是为了防止硬编码和暴力破解评分系统
I will show you why that is not true.
我会告诉你为什么这是不可能的
I kind of found a way to brute force the grader, but yeah.
我找到了一种暴力破解评分系统的方法  但不管怎样
And of course, lots of thinking and working a lot, meaning sleepless nights.
当然  这意味着大量的思考和工作  也就是不眠之夜
It was online back then.
那时候是在线上进行的
It was not in person.
不是面对面的
I remember working until like 5 a.m., 4 a.m.
我记得我工作到凌晨 5 点  4 点
for this project.
为了这个项目
Yeah, but let's go with my experience.
是的  但让我们继续我的经历
This is my bad plan for GitLit when I was a freshman.
这是我大一时为 Gitlet 制定的糟糕计划
I was creating the version control in my system.
我正在我的系统中创建版本控制
Didn't pay much attention to the soft parts of the project.
没有过多关注项目的软性部分
I said, you know what?
我说  你知道吗？
I'm just going to go for it.
我要放手一搏
I'm not going to take a look at the add, commit, or merge all of these soft parts of the project.
我不会去关注添加、提交或合并所有这些项目的软性部分
And I had no easy way to start designing.
而且我没有简单的方法开始设计
I wrote a couple of things to the design document, tried to come up with design that would work for everything main in the beginning.
我在设计文档里写了几点内容  试图在一开始就设计出一个能涵盖所有主要功能的方案
But what I thought was, oh, you know what?
但后来我想  哦  你知道吗？
My implementation is going to change after all, so I don't need a really detailed design document.
我的实现最终会改变的  所以我并不需要一个非常详细的设计文档
If I get stuck, I can just wait for people to ask questions on it.
如果我卡住了  我可以等别人来问我问题
And it's not that important to have a solid foundation now.
现在有一个坚实的基础并不那么重要
I'll get it later.
我以后会搞定的
So I was pretty lazy, and I didn't do anything about designing, or very small things.
所以我当时很懒  没有做任何关于设计的事情  或者只做了一些很小的设计
Consequently, I started coding immediately, and I didn't write any tests or think too hard about edge cases.
结果  我立即开始编码  没有写任何测试  也没有认真考虑极端情况
Yeah, so project was due April 2nd, and these are my comments from April 3rd and April 5th.
是的  项目截止日期是4月2日  这些是我在4月3日和4月5日的评论
The commit messages are all the same.
提交信息都是一样的
It's project two, or did someone work on project two?
这是项目2  还是有人在做项目2？
And if you go in one of these comments, you might even see a comment like just changing a typo or something different as well.
如果你查看其中一个评论  你甚至可能会看到类似“只是修改了一个错别字”或其他不同的评论
I did not realize my tests were failing because of this typo, so that was my last, I think, comment.
我没有意识到我的测试因为这个错别字而失败了  所以我想这是我的最后一个评论
And there were some people, throughout this process, there were some people basically removing their whole repository from Git.
在这个过程中  有一些人基本上是从Git中删除了他们的整个仓库
I assume you also maybe encountered this back in the time.
我猜你可能也遇到过这种情况
There's a guy says, hi, I just committed a push to my project, but my whole project has been deleted.
有个人说  嗨  我刚刚提交了一个推送我的项目的请求  但我的整个项目都被删除了
How can I recover my GitLit project file?
我怎样才能恢复我的GitLit项目文件？
Is it possible to do that? That guy was me.
有可能做到吗？ 那个人就是我
So I deleted my whole repository, and I had to start from the beginning, basically.
所以我删除了我的整个仓库  我基本上不得不从头开始
It's not fun, that I would say.
我得说  这不好玩
It's not really fun.
真的不好玩
And this is the grader.
这是评分器
Again, this is my experience.
再说一次  这是我的经验
This is what I've done. It is bad.
这是我做过的   很糟糕
Don't do this, OK?
别这么做  好吗？
Why am I telling you this?
我为什么要告诉你这些？
Some of the things were not effective.
有些事情没有效果
But despite having all of these struggles and everything, I still learned a lot.
但尽管遇到了所有这些困难  我仍然学到了很多
Oops. I think, sorry.
糟糕   我想  抱歉
Yeah, I still learned a lot.
是的  我仍然学到了很多
And it was a very big job from 6.18 to 6.1b.
从 6.18 到 6.1b  这是一项非常大的工作
From a skeleton code to nothing at all, I accomplished my first project, basically.
从一个框架代码到什么都没有  我基本上完成了我的第一个项目
And to this day, for every interview or job application, if they ask me about some kind of group project or any project that I've worked on, I always talk about GitLit.
直到今天  每次面试或求职  如果他们问我做过什么样的团队项目或任何项目  我都会谈论 GitLit
I learned a lot about the data structures and their implementations, like graph traversals, persistence,
我学到了很多关于数据结构及其实现的知识  比如图遍历、持久化和数据抽象
and data abstraction, and gained a lot of experience and different perspectives on how to approach problems.
并获得了许多关于如何处理问题的经验和不同的观点
But as you've seen, it's not the best project that I could have done in my life.
但正如你所看到的  这不是我一生中能做的最好的项目
So what if I'm wrong?
如果我错了怎么办？
I mostly ignore the principle from the Software Engineering 2 lecture.
我基本上忽略了软件工程 2 课程中的原理
I highly recommend it if you didn't watch it.
如果你还没看过  我强烈推荐你看一下
It's like time management, design and testing.
这就像时间管理、设计和测试
No tests, didn't design much at the start, and ended up running far behind.
没有测试  一开始也没有太多设计  结果进度远远落后
I failed many times and had to start from scratch repeatedly, like trial, tester, improvement, trial, data, and new design.
我失败了很多次  不得不反复从头开始  就像试验、测试、改进、试验、数据和新设计一样
Coded a lot while coding, tried to come up with different design, and finally, based a lot of time.
写了很多代码  尝试提出不同的设计  最后  花了很多时间
This is how I spend my time.
这就是我花费时间的方式
Reading the spec was 10%.
阅读规范占用了10%的时间
Design was 10%.
设计占用了10%的时间
Encoding was 80%.
编码占用了80%的时间
And for the next section, I would like to talk about whiteboarding and why it's going to be useful and what I've learned from GitLit, basically.
在下一部分  我想谈谈白板  以及为什么它会很有用  以及我从 GitLit 中学到了什么
So if you remember this slide from the previous section, there are a couple of things I would do differently now looking back.
所以  如果你还记得上一节的幻灯片  现在回顾起来  我会做一些不同的事情
The common issue is I coded a lot before designing or thinking, and it wasted my time on bad implementations.
常见的问题是  我在设计或思考之前写了很多代码  这浪费了我很多时间在糟糕的实现上
This is the time I spent for GitLit.
这是我花在 GitLit 上的时间
And if I do or redo things differently, this is what I would do right now.
如果我以不同的方式做事或重做  我现在就会这样做
The spec is still 10%, but design is going to take maybe 60% of my whole time, and coding is going to take 30%.
规范仍然是10%  但设计可能会占用我全部时间的60%  编码将占用30%
So if you remember my anecdote, my implementation is going to change after all, so I don't need a really detailed design doc.
所以  如果你还记得我的轶事  我的实现最终会改变  所以我并不需要一个非常详细的设计文档
Although this is somewhat true, it is still important to come up with an initial design, because it gives you a starting point and a fundamental point.
虽然这在某种程度上是正确的  但提出一个初始设计仍然很重要  因为它为你提供了一个起点和一个基本点
However, if the project is too big, how can you start designing in the first place, right?
然而  如果项目太大  你如何开始设计呢  对吧？
This is where the soft parts and whiteboarding comes along.
这就是软件部分和白板的用武之地
I didn't pay attention to the soft parts of the project, such as merge, add, or all other functions.
我没有关注项目的软件部分  例如合并、添加或所有其他函数
And as a solution, I would recommend picking up a pen and drawing out solutions to the small pieces at a time.
我建议你拿起笔  把解决方案一步一步地画出来
I would like to show you an image from GitLit videos.
我想给你展示一张来自GitLit视频的图片
When you take a look at this image, it's very hard to understand what's going on.
当你看到这张图片时  很难理解发生了什么
Yes, maybe there's like commit objects, and then they're on some kind of like a blockchain, and there's some files.
是的  也许有一些提交对象  然后它们在某种区块链上  还有一些文件
But as a freshman, when I was taking the class, these videos were also kind of hard to understand.
但作为一名新生  当我上这门课的时候  这些视频也很难理解
That's why it's very useful to use a marker and a pen or whatever you want to use.
这就是为什么使用马克笔、钢笔或任何你想要使用的工具是非常有用的
Two fundamental steps to write a program.
编写程序的两个基本步骤
There are two fundamental steps to write a program.
编写程序有两个基本步骤
Try to come up with an algorithm that solves a problem, that also goes into the two different fundamental steps as well.
试着想出一个解决问题的算法  这也分为两个不同的基本步骤
Find a solution in English or any other language of your own.
用英语或任何你自己的语言找到解决方案
Test yourself and try it and redo it.
测试你自己  尝试并重做
The second one is document it and convert it to pseudocode.
第二步是记录下来并将其转换为伪代码
And the second other fundamental steps for the writing program is converting this algorithm into a working code.
编写程序的另一个基本步骤是将算法转换为可执行代码
So first of all, you need to come up with an algorithm before coding it all.
所以首先  在编写代码之前  你需要想出一个算法
If you don't know what you're doing, as I did back in the time, you're going to waste a lot of time.
如果你不知道你在做什么  就像我以前一样  你会浪费很多时间
So converting first, coming with an algorithm that works, and then converting this algorithm into a working code is very crucial.
所以首先要转换  想出一个有效的算法  然后将这个算法转换为可执行代码  这是非常关键的
Whiteboarding allows us to start from the first step without a lot of friction, since it's a free flow process.
白板允许我们从第一步开始  没有太多的阻力  因为它是一个自由流动的过程
Pick up pen and paper and visualize what you're thinking.
拿起纸笔  把你正在想的东西形象化
Maybe it is going to help you a little bit more, or you're going to break down the parts even further.
也许它会对你有所帮助  或者你会把各个部分分解得更细
Separate the algorithm writing from coding.
将算法编写与编码分开
So coding is a different thing, and algorithm writing is a different thing.
所以说  写代码和写算法是两码事
If the algorithm is flawed, you spend less time or effort on the flawed algorithm
如果算法有问题  就不要在上面浪费时间和精力
而是要进一步将问题分解成更小的部分或最简单的版本
and break down the problem even further to little pieces or simplest versions.
So the whole idea of whiteboarding is, if you remember from 6.8 and 6.1 with recursion, there's a base case, right?
白板编程的整个概念是  如果你还记得6.8和6.1中的递归  它有一个基本情况  对吧？
The base case is the easier or the simplest way to kind of deal with some program.
基本情况是用最简单的方式来处理某个程序
So whiteboarding allows us to come to base case and understand better.
所以白板编程可以帮助我们找到基本情况  并更好地理解问题
Let's say you have a problem A. The problem A has problem sub-problem A1 and a sub-problem A1 and I. You ideate, visualize, test it, and modify it, and repeat it.
假设你有一个问题 A  它包含子问题 A1 和子问题 A2   你需要构思、可视化、测试、修改  然后重复这个过程
So you're simplifying a big problem.
所以你是在简化一个大问题
And by doing that, you're conveying your ideas and communicating with other people more easily.
这样做可以让你更容易地表达你的想法  并与其他人沟通
When you go to industry, you'll be working with teams.
当你进入职场后  你会与团队一起工作
Actually, you're working with people right now.
事实上  你现在就在与人合作
You're in project three and you have a group and you have a group partner.
你正在进行项目3  并且有一个小组和一个小组伙伴
So, sometimes there might be communication issues.
所以  有时候可能会出现沟通问题
Sometimes you guys are not on the same page.
有时候你们可能想法不一致
Whiteboarding allows you to convey your ideas and communicate with other people, which is very useful in the industry.
白板编程可以让你表达你的想法  并与其他人沟通  这在行业中非常有用
I would like to make a difference between whiteboarding and a design document here.
我想在这里区分一下白板编程和设计文档
So whiteboarding is when you are face-to-face with people with someone in the present, while design documents are for the future.
白板编程是你与其他人面对面交流时使用的  而设计文档是为将来准备的
Whiteboarding is for you and the people around you to understand the present time.
白板编程是为了让你和周围的人理解当前的问题
And a design doc is for another person you don't meet in the future that they'll tell them how to basically design things.
设计文档则是为了让未来不认识的人了解如何进行设计
So whiteboarding is in the moment.
所以白板编程是即时的
All right, any questions so far about whiteboarding?
好的  到目前为止  关于白板编程还有什么问题吗？
OK, let's go to the software engineering fundamentals first.
好  我们先来学习软件工程基础
I would like to give this analogy between architect and builder.
我想打个比方  就像建筑师和建筑工人一样
A computer engineering is like an architect.
计算机工程师就像建筑师
The architect is the one who plans out everything, like comes up with an initial plan, makes calculations, gives a proof of concept, and creates something new in the blueprint form.
建筑师负责规划一切  比如提出初步方案、进行计算、提供概念验证  并以蓝图的形式创造新的东西
A computer programmer is more like a builder.
计算机程序员更像建筑工人
The builder is the one who follows the specification.
建筑工人是按照规范施工的人
Given the blueprint or plan, it provides the end result.
给定蓝图或计划  它提供最终结果
It's very good at automating things if you know what you're doing, but you cannot come up with a new blueprint by itself.
如果你知道自己在做什么  它很擅长自动化  但它不能自己想出新的蓝图
This is also my personal experience as well.
这也是我个人的经验
When you see the large language models, like GPT, Devon, Gemini, Llama,
当我看到大型语言模型  比如LLM  比如GPT、Devon、Gemini、Llama
I was also considering, like, why did I choose this computer science thing?
我也在考虑  为什么我选择了计算机科学？
It looks like I'm going to be jobless, right?
看起来我要失业了  对吧？
But the thing is LLMs are not good at figuring out something new, at least for now, so we're good.
但问题是  LLM至少目前还不太擅长想出新东西  所以我们还好
So they're not good engineers.
所以他们不是好工程师
You are the engineer.
你才是工程师
The reason why we are here, why we are giving education, and we like the fundamental principles of this course is you are the engineer.
我们在这里的原因  我们提供教育的原因  以及我们喜欢这门课程的基本原则  是因为你才是工程师
You are the one who plans out things, and you create the blueprint.
你是那个规划事物并创建蓝图的人
Coming up with Blueprint from scratch can be very hard, but whiteboarding makes things easier to have the engineering mindset while making things smaller.
从头开始想出蓝图可能很难  但白板可以让你更容易拥有工程思维  同时把事情分解成更小的部分
Let's say you're going to build a house or some kind of skyscraper.
假设你要建造一座房子或某种摩天大楼
Instead of building everything at the same time, making things into smaller pieces and start from there will definitely help you.
与其同时建造所有东西  不如把事情分解成更小的部分  并从那里开始  这肯定会对你有所帮助
So split up the work one piece at a time.
所以  一次分解一个部分的工作
OK, so this part of the lecture is going to be a little bit interactive.
好的  这部分课程会有一些互动
So there's an example that I would like to give you.
这里有个例子想跟大家分享一下
You're a manager at a fintech company called Perihon, and you are going to hire a bunch of interns for the upcoming summer to two teams, one based in San Francisco and one based in New York.
你是 Perihon 这家金融科技公司的经理  今年夏天你要为旧金山和纽约的两个团队招聘一批实习生
Both teams need a certain number of people, and there are many more candidates that you have slots.
两个团队都需要一定数量的人员  并且候选人数量远远超过了岗位空缺
You want the best interns, but you also want to make interns happy.
你想要最优秀的实习生  但你也希望实习生们感到开心
Your boss has told you to figure it out without much further detail.
你的老板让你解决这个问题  但没有给出太多细节
How do you decide who to hire, and what aspects do you want to consider while hiring?
你如何决定雇佣谁  以及在雇佣过程中需要考虑哪些方面？
Let me check my time.
我看一下时间
I'll give you around maybe one or two minutes to discuss with your partners, or if you're by yourself, you can also discuss with yourself too.
我会给你们大约一到两分钟的时间与同伴讨论  或者如果你是独自一人  你也可以自己思考
Good afternoon.
下午好
Oops.
糟糕
Didn't see that.
没看到
All right.
好的
Can I have your attention once again, please?
请大家再次注意一下好吗？
Hello.
你好
Hello, hello, hello.
你好  你好  你好
Hi.
嗨
Okay.
好的
So, from your discussion, can you tell me a couple of things to figure this problem out?
那么  从你们的讨论中  你们能告诉我一些解决这个问题的方法吗？
Anybody?
有人吗？
Yes?
是吗？
Sure, and then based on their programming challenge, maybe you can assess their technical assessment, right?
当然  然后根据他们的编程挑战  也许你可以评估他们的技术评估  对吗？
Yeah. OK, that works.
好的  没问题
I saw a hand here, too.
我也看到这里有人举手了
I'd want to keep it more big, but I wanted to keep it diverse.
我想保持更大的规模  但我也想保持多元化
So I would just look at their performance as in how they've done with projects or stuff like that.
所以我只会看他们的表现  比如他们在项目中的表现等等
So just in general, their backgrounds and how they interact with other people.
所以总的来说  他们的背景以及他们与其他人的互动方式
That's a good way to approach this, so more holistic review.
这是一个很好的方法  所以更全面的审查
I'm just going to show you the way that I'm going to solve this problem.
我将向你展示我解决这个问题的方法
For simplicity, we model each in turn as having two aspects.
为了简单起见  我们将每个实习生建模为具有两个方面
Unfortunately, this time we were not diverse at all.
不幸的是  这次我们一点也不多元化
We just said we're going to care about technical skill, and that's it.
我们只是说我们要关心技术技能  仅此而已
So think about technical skill from integer score from 0 to 100.
所以考虑一下从 0 到 100 的整数分数的技术技能
And you can imagine that we collect this data from interviews, as we said, or technical assessment.
你可以想象我们从面试中收集这些数据  就像我们说的  或者技术评估
And the location preference, either SF or New York, can imagine that we collect this data from surveys the first time you apply for the job.
而地点偏好  无论是旧金山还是纽约  可以想象我们是在你第一次申请工作时从调查中收集这些数据的
All right. If an intern must be assigned to their unpreferred office, assign the intern with lower technical skill to the other office.
如果必须将实习生分配到他们不喜欢的办公室  则将技术技能较低的实习生分配到另一个办公室
That's also another thing that we like to do, because there might be some clashes between two offices.
这也是我们喜欢做的另一件事  因为两个办公室之间可能会有一些冲突
And if they have an unpreferred office, assign them an intern with a lower technical skill, basically.
如果他们有一个不喜欢的办公室  基本上就把技术技能较低的实习生分配给他们
Let's have this example and then visualize it.
咱们来看个例子  然后把它视觉化
Let's say San Francisco has three people, and New York also has three people.
假设旧金山和纽约各有三个职位空缺
And you have all of these people right now.
现在有一堆人来应聘
They apply for your company.
他们申请加入你的公司
It's Alice, Kevin, Steven, Alex, Samog, Michael, and Victoria.
他们分别是 Alice、Kevin、Steven、Alex、Samog、Michael 和 Victoria
And they have all of their technical skills or assessments right here.
他们的技术能力评估结果都在这里
A new way to do this is the end result should be something like this.
最终结果应该像这样
The ones who scored the best are going to be assigned to their locations, like, for example, SF and New York.
得分最高的人会被分配到他们想要去的地区  比如旧金山和纽约
Look at Michael right here.
看看 Michael 的情况
Michael really wanted to go to SF, but was not good enough to go to SF, but was still good enough to go to New York City.
Michael 真的很想去旧金山  但他的能力还达不到旧金山的标准  不过去纽约还是绰绰有余
So I just placed Michael to New York City.
所以我把 Michael 分配到了纽约
This kind of like introduced the second part of this lecture, or like software engineering fundamentals.
这就引出了本讲座的第二部分  也就是软件工程基础
So how do you solve this problem then?
那么  如何解决这个问题呢？
Like, OK, I defined a problem.
好  我已经定义了一个问题
There are a couple of constraints.
还有一些限制条件
How do you solve this?
你怎么解决这个问题？
I will give you two, three minutes to discuss with your partner.
我给你们两三分钟时间和你的伙伴讨论一下
And I'll explain the answer.
然后我会解释答案
So again, as a reminder, Your primary goal, hire the interns with the highest technical skill.
再提醒一下   你的首要目标是  招募技术能力最强的实习生
And the secondary goal is assign the interns their preferred office if possible.
第二个目标是尽可能地将实习生分配到他们首选的办公室
Go. Thank you.
开始吧   谢谢
Thank you.
All right.
好的
I think that was a little bit good time to stop there.
我认为现在停下来是个不错的时机
So I'd like to hear your opinions.
我想听听你们的意见
How do you solve this problem?
你们会如何解决这个问题？
Any ideas?
有什么想法吗？
Yes.
有
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
OK, so the students said to reiterate for the Zoom.
好的  所以学生们说要为 Zoom 重申一下
Students said, we can rank them and kind of like sort them in an order.
学生们说  我们可以对他们进行排名  并按顺序进行排序
And we can give the preference for the top people.
我们可以优先考虑排名靠前的人
And if the offices are full now, from there, we can try to fill out the other office.
如果办公室现在已经满了  我们可以尝试从那里开始填补其他办公室
That works.
这可行
Any other people who wants to share their thoughts?
还有其他人想分享他们的想法吗？
OK, that's fine.
好的  没关系
So the main solution will be sort the interns based on their technical assessments,
所以主要的解决方案是根据技术评估对实习生进行排序
so Victoria, Alex, Amal, Kevin, Steven, Michael, and Alice, and fill up the locations.
如维多利亚、亚历克斯、阿迈勒、凯文、史蒂文、迈克尔和爱丽丝  然后填补这些职位
So as you remember from the previous slide, the locations now have a capacity of three.
正如你从上一张幻灯片中回忆到的  这些职位现在的容量是三个
And this will give you n log n time, n being the number of interns applied.
这将给你 N log N 的时间  n 是申请实习生的数量
For now, let's assume for the simplicity we have seven interns, but n might be by 1,000, 2,000, or a very huge number, right?
为了简单起见  我们假设现在有七个实习生  但 N 可能是 1,000、2,000 或一个非常大的数字  对吧？
Since you're sorting these people based on their rank, the sorting algorithm generally takes n log n, depending on which one you're using.
由于你根据排名对这些人进行排序  排序算法通常需要 N log N 的时间  具体取决于你使用哪种算法
But if you want to use the fastest one, it's going to take n log n. So I'll assign Victoria to SF.
但如果你想使用最快的算法  它将需要 N log N 的时间  所以我将把维多利亚分配到旧金山
Alex is SF.
亚历克斯到旧金山
Amag is New York.
阿迈勒到纽约
And then Kevin is SF.
然后凯文到旧金山
Michael is New York, because SF was full now.
迈克尔到纽约  因为旧金山现在已经满了
Poor Alice is not going to be able to be chosen.
可怜的爱丽丝将无法被选中
Can we do better?
我们能做得更好吗？
Is there a better algorithm that I can come up with that is going to be more efficient?
我能不能想出一个更有效的算法？
Yes?
有吗？
Well, maybe you use two priority queues, one for each location.
嗯  也许你可以使用两个优先队列  每个地点一个
And then you basically add this.
然后你基本上添加这个
Basically, if the score is there, it has to be stuck in the priority queue for either location.
基本上  如果分数在那里  它必须卡在任一地点的优先队列中
Then you put it in there.
然后你把它放在那里
And then if it's not, you just get rid of it.
然后如果不是  你就把它去掉
So that way, you don't have to go through the list.
这样一来  你就不必遍历整个列表
So the student said you can use two priority queues for the offices.
所以学生说可以用两个优先队列来表示办公室
And once you're done with the, I guess, filling them out, you don't need to consider the rest of it, right?
一旦你完成了填写它们  我猜  你就不需要考虑剩下的部分了  对吧？
No. I mean, if you don't have to sort the list in advance, you can just add, like,
不   我的意思是  如果你不需要提前对列表进行排序  你可以添加  比如
Q&A
问答
OK, yeah, OK, OK.
好的  是的  好的  好的
So the student said, I'll actually explain the answer because the answer is also what the student answered.
所以学生说  我实际上会解释答案  因为答案也是学生回答的
We can do, in this case, better.
在这种情况下  我们可以做得更好
So let me go to whiteboarding once again.
所以让我再去白板那里
Our naive approach works, but it is slow when n is a huge number, the number of slots we have available.
我们天真的方法有效  但是当 N 是一个巨大的数字  也就是我们可用的槽位数量时  它会很慢
We can do better. Let's come up with a design.
我们可以做得更好   让我们来想出一个设计
Pretend like the interns come one at a time and keep track of preferences and technical skills of interns, as well as the capacity of both locations.
假装实习生一次来一个  并跟踪实习生的偏好和技术技能  以及两个地点的容量
Don't forget about our primary and secondary goal.
不要忘记我们的主要和次要目标
Hire the interns with the highest technical skill and assign the interns their preferred office if possible.
雇用技术技能最高的实习生  并尽可能将实习生分配到他们喜欢的办公室
If an intern must be assigned to their unpreferred office, assign the intern with the lower technical skill to the other office.
如果实习生必须被分配到他们不喜欢的办公室  则将技术技能较低的实习生分配到另一个办公室
So let's start from scratch.
所以让我们从头开始
And assume I have, I don't know, like a billion applications now.
假设我现在有  我不知道  十亿份申请
I'm hiring everything, everybody I apply to my company right now.
我现在正在雇佣每一个申请我公司的人
So start with Intern A, right?
所以从实习生 A 开始  对吧？
Intern A is, I don't know the technical skill right now, but I don't really care because SF location is empty.
实习生 A 现在技术水平还不清楚  但因为旧金山办公室还有空位  所以没关系
So I'm just going to put it.
所以我会先把他安排到那
B comes here, MT.
B 来到这  蒙大拿州
C comes here.
C 来到这
What about D?
那 D 呢？
So D wants SF, but SF is full now.
D 想去旧金山  但是旧金山办公室现在满了
At this point, if you remember our primary goal, all of the interns taking the skills, let's say,
这时候  如果你还记得我们的首要目标  所有实习生都要参加技术评估
if you remember our primary goal, we want to hire the best interns.
假设你还记得我们的首要目标  我们想要招聘最优秀的实习生
So if these technical assessment is better than any of these people, A, B, C, in SF location, I want to be able to swap with them.
所以  如果这些技术评估结果比旧金山办公室的 A、B、C 任何一个人都好  我想能够和他们交换
All of the interns taking the skills in SF unfortunately greater than D. So I'm going to put D into New York.
不幸的是  所有在旧金山参加技术评估的实习生的水平都比 D 高  所以我会把 D 安排到纽约
And then ENF, I filled it out.
然后纽约办公室就满了
Now there's another intern coming up, intern G. And intern G wants to go to SF.
现在又来了一个实习生  实习生 G  实习生 G 也想去旧金山
It is full.
但是已经满了
So I'm going to compare.
所以我来比较一下
Remember the first objective.
记住第一个目标
I'm going to compare all of these technical assessments.
我会比较所有这些技术评估的结果
Rather than comparing all of them, actually, I'm going to compare the minimum one in SF.
实际上  与其比较所有人的结果  我会比较旧金山办公室里最低的那个
Because if I can swap the minimum one with G, if that's possible, that is going to give me the highest ranking.
因为如果我可以把最低的那个和 G 交换  如果可能的话  那将会给我最高的排名
Replace the minimum with incoming one, if possible.
如果可能  用新来的替换最低的那个
Let's say G's technical skill was better than A, so G and A was replaced.
假设 G 的技术水平比 A 好  那么 G 和 A 就会被替换
But I can still put A somewhere else.
但我仍然可以把 A 安排到其他地方
A's preference was SF.
A的首选是旧金山
But it can still go to New York.
但是他仍然可以去纽约
I still want higher skilled individuals in my company, right?
我还是希望公司里都是高技能人才  对吧？
So I will check whether anybody in New York office has minimum technical assessment than A. And then in this case, it will.
所以我将检查纽约办公室是否有人技术评估最低分比A高  在这种情况下  确实有
I'm going to replace that.
我将会替换那个人
And then unfortunately, E is going to be cut.
然后不幸的是  E将会被裁掉
So E is not going to SF or New York City.
所以E不会去旧金山或纽约
This is very important.
这很重要
This is what I've done.
这就是我所做的
So I replace A and G. And now A is about to go to New York because E's value is less than A, apparently.
所以我替换了A和G  现在A要去纽约了  因为显然E的价值低于A
And E is cut.
而E被裁掉了
I repeated all of this for a bunch of interns now, and I have this solution, or I guess the final results.
我对很多实习生都重复了这个过程  现在我有了这个解决方案  或者说最终结果
So OKBC, LK, AI, NJ, and FA.
也就是OKBC  LK  AI  NJ和FA
These are the intern names.
这些是实习生的名字
They are replaced in SF and New York City now.
他们现在在旧金山和纽约被替换了
So repeat, and the final result is this one.
重复一遍  最终结果是这样的
The thing that I did here was getting the minimum element each time, right?
我在这里做的事情是每次都得到最小元素  对吧？
I want to get the minimum element each time from SF and New York City.
我想要每次都从旧金山和纽约获得最小元素
I don't want to compare every single one that already exists in the office, because that's going to have a lot of overhead.
我不想比较办公室里已经存在的每一个人  因为那样会产生很多开销
It's not going to be very efficient.
这样效率不高
And how can I reorganize this in some type of data structure, I guess?
我猜想  我该如何将这些信息重新组织成某种数据结构呢？
And the students said prior to Q, it is correct.
学生们在 Q 之前说  这是正确的
In this case, we'll use a min heap.
在这种情况下  我们将使用最小堆
Use a custom comparator to compare the technical skills of applicants.
使用自定义比较器来比较申请人的技术技能
So if you remember the heap, there's one max heap and min heap.
所以如果你还记得堆的话  那里有一个最大堆和最小堆
And if you want to get the minimum element or the maximum element, it is going to take you constant time, which I really want.
如果你想得到最小元素或最大元素  它将花费你恒定的时间  这正是我想要的
So you can use min heap to compare the technical assessment of both interns.
所以你可以使用最小堆来比较两个实习生的技术评估
That's how I would call it.
我就是这么称呼它的
So solution 1, to reiterate and recap, solution 1, sort the interns, take the top interns, and the time complexity is going to be n log n.
所以解决方案1  重申和概括一下  解决方案1  对实习生进行排序  选取最优秀的实习生  时间复杂度将是N log N
And solution 2, iterate through interns one by one, check preference and location capacities, place interns, and the time complexity is going to be n log k, k is being the capacity.
解决方案2  逐个遍历实习生  检查偏好和地点容量  安排实习生  时间复杂度将是N log K  k是容量
So the k is 3.
所以k是3
I guarantee you, in almost these kind of questions, k is going to be very less valid compared to n,
我向你保证  在几乎所有这类问题中  k与n相比都将是非常小的值
because n is, as we learn from the asymptotic sector, it's huge.
因为n  正如我们从渐近分析中学到的  它是巨大的
So, n log k is going to be significantly better than n log n.
所以  N log K将明显优于N log N
One thing that I did here, I didn't code anything, right?
我在这里做的一件事是  我没有编写任何代码  对吧？
I just showed you a couple of diagrams, circles, colors, and we were able to figure out what we could have done.
我只是给你展示了几张图表、圆圈、颜色  我们就能够弄清楚我们可以做什么
We didn't code directly after solution one.
我们在解决方案一之后没有直接编写代码
We realized that we could do better.
我们意识到我们可以做得更好
And without thinking about the data structures at first, we came up with a better solution.
而且在没有首先考虑数据结构的情况下  我们想出了一个更好的解决方案
Fun fact, by the way, this exactly same This question was asked to me during one of the final interviews that I was doing with one of the companies.
顺便说一句  有趣的是  这个问题是在我与其中一家公司进行的最后一次面试中被问到的
I'm not going to name it.
我不会说出它的名字
And it was actually in person.
而且实际上是当面进行的
And I didn't code anything.
我也没有写任何代码
I just draw out something.
我只是画了一些东西
And I was like, oh, if this wasn't coding, I'm pretty sure I would fail.
我当时想  哦  如果这不是编程  我肯定我会挂科
But when you use pen or marker or whiteboarding, basically, it gets easier to understand and visualize.
但当你使用钢笔、马克笔或白板时  基本上  理解和可视化就更容易了
So that's the next topic that I want to talk about.
所以这就是我接下来要谈的话题
The idea of a heap is very different when you're whiteboarding versus when you're coding, right?
当你在白板上画图和写代码时  堆的概念是非常不同的  对吧？
When you're coding, if you've seen the lab coding, like LRBs, it's very, very painful.
当你编写代码时  如果你见过实验室的代码  比如 LRBs  那真是太痛苦了
There's so many things to debug.
有太多东西需要调试
From a higher perspective level, it's fine.
从更高的角度来看  这没什么问题
You understand it. But coding is very hard.
你理解它   但编码非常难
At the higher level of algorithm design, you don't even think about a tree or heap.
在更高的算法设计层面  你甚至不会考虑树或堆
I want to put something and get the minimum value very fast.
我想放一些东西进去  然后很快得到最小值
And this will lead me to the solution.
这将引导我找到解决方案
Don't worry about the interfaces, how you put them, how you get them, underlying variables or API calls.
不要担心接口、如何放置它们、如何获取它们、底层变量或 API 调用
And while whiteboarding, we broke the problem down into different steps and came up with the MinHip structure.
在白板上画图时  我们将问题分解成不同的步骤  并提出了最小堆结构
It came up naturally.
它是自然而然产生的
Visualization helped a lot with the domain knowledge.
可视化对领域知识的帮助很大
So if you remember from the ADT lectures or discussion, for example, come up with unique IDs.
所以  如果你还记得 ADT 课程或讨论的内容  例如  想出唯一的 ID
What do you use there?
你用什么方法？
You use a set.
你用的是集合
You don't really know how a set works or how you code it, but you are going to use it.
你可能不太清楚集合的运作方式或者如何编写代码  但是你会用到它
So it's kind of like a black box.
所以它就像一个黑盒子
Or match the partners.
或者匹配搭档
If you're going to match something to something, you're kind of like mapping values, right?
如果你要将某个东西与另一个东西匹配  你就是在进行值映射  对吧？
So you're going to use map.
所以你会使用映射
That's how whiteboarding allows you to break down these challenging problems and come up with a really good solution.
这就是白板如何帮助你分解这些具有挑战性的问题并提出一个非常好的解决方案
By the way, this is a very challenging problem.
顺便说一下  这是一个非常具有挑战性的问题
I would say, like, they asked me in the final interview, and I will say, like, if they asked me in a coding sense, I would actually fail.
我想说  就像  他们在最终面试中问过我  我会说  如果他们在编码方面问我  我实际上会失败
But yeah, now I'm going to go to the next part, how to practice, right?
但是  是的  现在我要进入下一部分  如何练习  对吧？
Most of us here are maybe taking this course to go to industry for data structures and algorithms.
我们中的大多数人可能正在学习这门课程  以便在数据结构和算法领域进入行业
So these challenge problems are going to be asked for you while you're also interviewing.
所以在面试过程中  你也会被问到这些具有挑战性的问题
How do you get better at these problems?
你如何才能更好地解决这些问题？
There are tons of resources. First one is lead coding.
有很多资源   第一个是 LeetCode
It's the most popular or the most conventional way, I guess, used for job applications and interviews.
我想  这是求职和面试中最流行或最传统的方式
Easy to medium-scale programming questions.
简单到中等规模的编程问题
That was also a lead code problem.
那也是一道 LeetCode 问题
You can check that out.
你可以去看看
I think it's TopK Minhee question or something like that.
我觉得是TopK Minhee问题或者类似的问题
Code forces, I didn't know if this existed, but it's harder than lead codes
Codeforces  我不知道这个是否存在  但它比LeetCode更难
and it's for CS Olympiad style questions, like it's in the format of CS Olympiad.
它是针对CS奥林匹克竞赛风格的问题  就像CS奥林匹克竞赛的格式一样
Project Euler. It is more math-based, algorithm-design focused.
Project Euler   它更偏向于数学  专注于算法设计
Our goal is to find the answer without caring too much about your actual coding.
我们的目标是找到答案  而不必太在意你的实际编码
Cryptopulse, niche problems about computer security, and then SpaceCam, TIS 800, A equals to B, Bombay, 7 million humans, and et cetera.
Cryptopals  关于计算机安全的特殊问题  然后是SpaceChem、TIS-800/A=B/Bombe/7 Billion Humans等等
They are also programming-style video games.
它们也是编程风格的电子游戏
And then built-in incentive structure and difficulty curve, so very good for developing skills.
然后内置激励结构和难度曲线  所以非常适合开发技能
So there are so many resources for you to be able to get better at these challenge problems.
所以有很多资源可以帮助你更好地解决这些挑战问题
I personally never used GoPort's Project Order Crypto Palace or any other video games.
我个人从未使用过Google Code Jam、Project Euler、Cryptopals或任何其他电子游戏
But Justin showed me, and I think Project Order is very cool.
但Justin向我展示了  我认为Project Euler非常酷
It allows you to do more whiteboarding than any other options, in my opinion.
在我看来  它比其他任何选择都更能让你进行白板编程
That being said, Let's go to example lead code question.
话虽如此   我们来看一个LeetCode的例子
One thing that we never taught you in these classes, or actually, we teach you these data structure or lead code questions.
在这些课程中  我们从未教过你的一件事  或者说  我们教过你这些数据结构或LeetCode问题
If you remember from project two or project three, there are some challenging problems, common ancestors.
如果你还记得项目2或项目3  有一些具有挑战性的问题  比如共同祖先
I don't know, get the top K words.
我不知道  获取Top K个单词
All of these kind of problems are actually lead code problems hidden into these projects.
所有这类问题实际上都是隐藏在这些项目中的LeetCode问题
Let's say I want to give you a straight-up ethical question.
假设我想给你一个直接的LeetCode问题
Given the head of a singly linked list, reverse the list and return the reverse list.
给定一个单链表的头节点  反转该链表并返回反转后的链表
There's an example right here.
这里有个例子
So 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 is going to be 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
所以 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 会变成 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
And the 1, 2 is going to be 2, 1.
而 1, 2 会变成 2, 1
So the input is going to be head, linked list.
所以输入将会是 head  链表
You can say, you can assume that it's going to have a dot next and dot value or something like that.
你可以说  你可以假设它将会有一个点 next 和点 value 或者类似的东西
And the output is going to be 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
而输出将会是 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
I will give you two, three minutes, and then I'll show you the answer.
我给你们两三分钟  然后我会展示答案
By the way, you don't have to code.
顺便说一下  你们不需要编码
It's whiteboarding.
这是白板编程
It's just, tell me how you think it's going to be solution B.
就是  告诉我你们认为解决方案 B 会是什么样
Sorry?
抱歉？
It doesn't matter.
没关系
It can be ordered.
它可以是有序的
It cannot be ordered.
它可以是无序的
It doesn't matter.
没关系
All right, one minute and I'll get some answers from you.
好的  一分钟后我会从你们那里得到一些答案
All right, for the sake of time, let's hear some answers from you first, and I'll reveal the answer.
好的  为了节省时间  让我们先听听你们的一些答案  然后我会揭晓答案
There are a couple of things, a couple of ways to solve this problem.
有几种方法可以解决这个问题
Anybody wants to give an answer?
有人想给个答案吗？
Please.
I'll be very sad.
我会很伤心的
Yes?
是吗？
Can you try having two pointers, one pointing to the end of the link, plus one pointing to the next, and then ints?
你可以尝试使用两个指针  一个指向链表的末尾  另一个指向下一个  然后再使用整型吗？
Well, you're on the good track.
嗯  你的思路是对的
You're on the good track.
你的思路是对的
You might be missing a one more pointer.
你可能还缺少一个指针
Any other answers?
还有其他答案吗？
Yes?
有吗？
You have a recursive function that keeps track of the previous, and then you can post recursion.
你有一个递归函数来跟踪前一个节点  然后你可以在递归后进行操作
You change the next to the previous.
你把下一个节点改成前一个节点
I think that works.
我觉得这可行
Yes, that's one way to do recursive approach.
是的  这是一种递归方法
If you do iterative, does anybody want to answer how to do iterative?
如果你用迭代的方式  有人想回答如何进行迭代吗？
Yes?
有吗？
Yes, yes, that would work.
是的  是的  那会奏效的
So the answer is you have your linked list right here.
所以答案就是你这里有你的链表
You have your previous and current, as well as next pointers.
你有你的前一个指针、当前指针和下一个指针
So you said there should be a current and next pointer, but you should also have a previous
所以你说应该有一个当前指针和下一个指针  但也应该有一个前一个指针
so you can keep track of what the previous value is so you can revert it back.
这样你就可以跟踪前一个值是什么  以便你可以把它恢复回去
I will start from the first one.
我将从第一个开始
I will make sure that now current's next value is now previous.
我要确保现在当前的下一个值是前一个值
And I'm going to shift my pointers to the right side, one right side.
我把指针移到右边  就右边一个
Now I'm at 2.
现在我在2的位置
I'm going to take 2's pointer right here, or the next pointer.
我要把2的指针  或者说下一个指针拿过来
I'm going to make sure it's pointing out the previous, and then do the same thing once again.
我要确保它指向之前那个  然后再做一次同样的事情
See?
看到了吗？
And next pointer here, so I can keep track of this one, so I can continue iterating through.
还有这里的下一个指针  这样我就能跟踪这个  然后继续迭代
And I will go to the next one, change the pointer, go to the next one, change the pointer, go to the next one, change the pointer, and then I'll be done.
然后我会转到下一个  更改指针  再转到下一个  更改指针  再转到下一个  更改指针  然后就完成了
Because the current is null right now, or none, so you're going to be done.
因为现在的current是空的  或者说没有  所以就完成了
That was great. I have another question right here.
太棒了   我这里还有另一个问题
It's from Project Euler.
它来自Project Euler
Find the minimal pass sum from top left to bottom right by only moving right and down.
找出从左上角到右下角的最小路径和  只能向右或向下移动
So you can only go right and down in matrix.txt.
所以你只能在matrix.txt中向右或向下移动
Right-click and save.
右键单击并保存
This is for just the submissions.
这只是为了提交
And for your convenience, I'm just going to put it here.
为了方便起见  我就把它放在这里
So you can only go right and down, and you need to give the minimal pass sum from top left to bottom right.
所以你只能向右或向下移动  你需要给出从左上角到右下角的最小路径和
Important thing here, I'm going to make an emphasize, a minimal path sum.
这里重要的事情  我要强调一下  是最小路径和
This might hint you something.
这可能会给你一些提示
So I'll leave you like two minutes or like a, yeah, actually two minutes to work on it by yourself, and then I will rebuild the answer.
所以我会给你两分钟左右  嗯  实际上是两分钟让你自己解决这个问题  然后我会重建答案
It doesn't have to be diagonal all the time.
路径不一定非得是斜的
It might be like L-shaped.
它可以是L形的
It has to be a minimal path.
它必须是最短路径
That's my objective.
这就是我的目标
Thank you.
谢谢你
All right, so I'd like to hear your answers.
好的  我想听听你们的答案
Anybody wants the answer?
有人想回答吗？
Yes?
有吗？
So basically, you're going to have 2D array.
所以基本上  你将拥有一个二维数组
2D array. And then you can initialize everything to infinity, except the first element, 0, 0.
二维数组   然后你可以将所有元素初始化为无穷大  除了第一个元素  0, 0
And then you're going to go over it normally.
然后你将像平常一样遍历它
And then when you're at 5j, you're going to take the minimum of taking
当你位于 5j 时  你将取以下两个值的最小值：
I see.
我明白了
I think that's a dynamic programming type of thing, right?
我认为这是一种动态规划类型的东西  对吧？
Yes, it works, yeah.
是的  它有效
It's one of the solutions.
这是解决方案之一
Anybody also wants to answer this?
还有其他人想回答这个问题吗？
Yes?
有吗？
I think 3D Recursion would be... It works, but it's going to be slow.
我认为三维递归可以...它有效  但会很慢
There's an error algorithm to do that.
有个错误算法可以做到这一点
And we've seen this in lecture.
我们在课上见过
Yes?
是吗？
DFS.
深度优先搜索（DFS）
But in DFS, we don't really care about the edge weights, right?
但在DFS中  我们并不关心边的权重  对吧？
In DFS, we also do not care about the edge weights, too.
在DFS中  我们也不关心边的权重
But you're on the right track.
但你的方向是对的
Yes?
是吗？
Mm-hmm. That is right.
嗯哼   没错
So I have this graph right here, right?
所以我这里有一个图  对吧？
I have this matrix, I guess.
我有一个矩阵  我想
I am going to represent all of these numbers as nodes.
我将把所有这些数字表示为节点
And I'm going to create a dummy node.
我要创建一个虚拟节点
Because in order to assign some weights to the edges, the first one, 131, should be in the edge itself, right?
因为为了给边分配一些权重  第一个131应该在边本身  对吧？
So I'm going to create a dummy node.
所以我将创建一个虚拟节点
And I'm going to make sure that I'm going to put all of these values, like 131, 201, 630, 537, 805, to the edge weights right here.
我将确保把所有这些值  比如131、201、630、537、805  都放在这里的边权重上
And after that, for the simplicity, I didn't show all of the numbers right here.
在那之后  为了简单起见  我没有在这里显示所有的数字
But you can assume all of these numbers are going to be edge weights, going from one location, or one pixel, or one ij value to the other ij value.
但你可以假设所有这些数字都将是边的权重  从一个位置、一个像素或一个ij值到另一个ij值
And if you run Dijkstra's, that will be efficient enough.
如果你运行Dijkstra算法  那将足够有效
So it's like BFS, DFS, or tree recursion works, but it is going to explore everything.
所以就像 BFS、DFS 或树的递归  它们都能工作  但会遍历所有内容
In Dijkstra's, we don't really like the instance.
在 Dijkstra 算法中  我们不太喜欢这种情况
It's going to give the shortest path.
它会给出最短路径
It's going to be more efficient.
它会更有效率
And for DFS and BFS, yes, that's the right way to go, like the right approach initially.
对于 DFS 和 BFS  是的  一开始它们是正确的方法
But since we have edge weights, in that moment, we need to use Dijkstra's.
但由于我们有边权重  这时就需要使用 Dijkstra 算法
And that would be the end of my lecture.
我的课就讲到这里
Thanks for coming. And if you have any questions, please let me know.
谢谢大家   如果有任何问题  请告诉我
Anything about industry, personal experience, and everything, I'm always open.
任何关于行业、个人经验和所有事情  我都很乐意分享
And yeah, I'll see you next week, hopefully.
好的  希望下周再见
Do project three.
做第三个项目
Yeah.
好的
What is there to care about here?
这里有什么要注意的吗？